redboxinstant.com 2016-12-29

# Redbox Privacy Policy | Redbox customer Privacy Policy

**Privacy Policy**   
Our Privacy Policy has been updated and has an effective date of November 30, 2016.

This Privacy Policy describes our practices regarding the collection, use and disclosure of information collected by Redbox Automated Retail, LLC (doing business in Texas as DVD Rental by Redbox LLC) (“ **Redbox** ”) through our web sites, kiosks, applications, and other online services that post or include a link to this Privacy Policy (collectively, the “ **Redbox Platforms** ”). This Privacy Policy only covers information collected on the Redbox Platforms and does not cover any information collected at any other web site or elsewhere by Redbox (unless specifically stated).

Please review this Privacy Policy carefully. In addition, please review the [ **Terms of Use**](http://www.redbox.com/rentalterms), which govern your use of the Redbox Platforms.

**TABLE OF CONTENTS**

  * CHANGES TO THE PRIVACY POLICY
  * THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT

    * Information You Provide Us
    * Information We Collect Automatically
    * Information Third Parties Provide About You and Social Media Interactions
    * OUR USE OF INFORMATION COLLECTED THROUGH THE REDBOX PLATFORMS

  * CHILDREN
  * COMMUNITY FORUMS
  * DISCLOSURE OF INFORMATION TO THIRD PARTIES
    * When You Request That We Share Your Information
    * Third Parties Providing Services on Our Behalf
    * Sweepstakes, Contests and Promotions
    * Administrative and Legal Reasons
    * Business Transfers
  * THIRD-PARTY ADVERTISING AND ANALYTICS COMPANIES
  * HOW WE RESPOND TO “DO NOT TRACK” SIGNALS
  * CHANGING YOUR INFORMATION
  * YOUR CHOICES
  * Marketing Emails and Mobile Messages
  * YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS
  * THIRD PARTY CONTENT, SITES & DEVICES 
  * SECURITY
  * CONSENT TO TRANSFER

**CHANGES TO THE PRIVACY POLICY**  
Redbox reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time without prior notice and will notify you of material changes by posting the changed or modified Privacy Policy on the Redbox Platforms. We may also provide notice to you in other ways in our discretion, such as through contact information you have provided. Any changes will be effective immediately upon the posting of the revised Privacy Policy unless otherwise specified and your continued use of the any of the Redbox Platforms after the effective date of the revised Privacy Policy will constitute your consent to those changes. However, Redbox will not make material changes to how it treats previously collected Personal Information about you without providing notice and giving you the chance to consent (opt-in or opt-out).  Note, however, that you may need to consent to our new policies in order to continue to use the Redbox Platforms and our services.

**THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT AND HOW WE USE IT**

**Information You Provide Us**  
We may ask you to provide personally identifiable information, which is information that identifies you as a specific identified individual, such as your name, phone number, or e-mail address (collectively, “ **Personal Information** ”), and other information about you, such as payment information, demographic information (for example, your gender, age or similar information). Certain features may also collect information about your preferences and interests. If we combine demographic, preference-related or similar information with the Personal Information we collect, we will treat that combined information as Personal Information under this Privacy Policy.

**Information We Collect Automatically**  
We and third-party advertising companies and service providers may use a variety of technologies that automatically or passively collect certain information whenever you visit any Redbox Platform or otherwise interact with us or our content (“ **Usage Information** ”). Usage Information may include the hardware model, browser, and operating system you are using, the URL or advertisement that referred you to the Redbox Platform you are visiting, all of the areas within the Redbox Platforms that you visit, your time zone, location information, and mobile network (if applicable), among other information. In addition, we automatically collect your IP address or other unique identifier (“ **Device Identifier** ”) for any computer, mobile phone or other device you use to access our Redbox Platforms. In some cases, we may directly collect location information through your device. You may be able to turn off the collection of location information through the settings on your device. Usage Information is generally non-identifying, but if Redbox associates it with you as a specific and identifiable person, Redbox treats it as Personal Information.

The methods that may be used to collect Usage Information include the following:

**Cookies** **and Local Storage**   
Cookies and local storage are data files placed within a browser on a device when it is used to visit a Redbox Platform. Certain web browsers and browser add-ons, such as Adobe Flash, may provide additional local data storage mechanisms. For example, a Flash cookie is a data file placed on a device via the Adobe Flash plugin. Cookies and local storage can be used for a variety of purposes, including to store a unique identifier for your device that recognizes your device as you visit the Redbox Platforms or other web sites or online services and to remember your preferences. Most browsers provide you with the ability to disable or decline cookies and local storage.  You will need to check your browser’s settings for further information. For more information about Flash and the privacy choices Adobe offers, visit <http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html>. If you choose to disable cookies or to adjust your Flash privacy settings on your device, some features of a Redbox Platform may not function properly. 

**Web Beacons**  
Small graphic images or other web programming code called web beacons (also known as “1x1 GIFs” or “clear GIFs”), may be included in our web pages and e-mail messages.  Web beacons or similar technologies may be used for a number of purposes, including, without limitation, to count visitors to a Redbox Platform, to monitor how users navigate a Redbox Platform, to count how many e-mails that were sent were actually opened or to count how many particular videos or links were actually viewed.

In addition, we may use these and a variety of other technologies that collect Usage Information and similar information for security and fraud detection purposes and to enforce our intellectual property rights.  This includes the use of digital rights management technology that is embedded in DVDs, streamed content or other content provided by Redbox in order to prevent theft and unauthorized access to content, and to protect the intellectual property rights of Redbox and content owners.

**Information Third Parties Provide About You and Social Media Interactions**  
Redbox may receive information about you from third parties, including business partners and data providers. You may also have the opportunity to interact with a third-party application or feature available through a Redbox Platform, such as features that allow you to log-in through, access, or otherwise connect your account on a third-party service (e.g., Facebook or Twitter). If you choose to utilize such a third-party service, we will receive information about you from that third-party service (which may include Personal Information) and they may receive information about your use of the Redbox Platforms.  Through these features, third parties may collect your IP address or other Device Identifier, which page you are visiting on a Redbox Platform, and may set cookies to enable the third party feature to function properly. If you choose to post information to a third party platform, that information may be public. **  You acknowledge that, if you choose to post any information about your movie or other rentals or viewing history on a third-party platform or in a Redbox community forum (described below), the Video Privacy Protection Act ****of** **1998 (18 U.S.C. § 2710) (or any similar state law) does not apply.   ****However, to the extent it does apply in any manner, you are providing your informed, written consent to the disclosure of that information pursuant to the Video Privacy Protection Act.** ****

We may combine the information we receive from those other sources with information we collect through the Redbox Platforms. In those cases, we will apply this Privacy Policy to the combined information. The information collected and stored by the third party is subject solely to the third party’s privacy practices.

**OUR USE OF INFORMATION COLLECTED THROUGH THE REDBOX PLATFORMS**  
Redbox may use information collected through the Redbox Platforms, including Usage Information and Personal Information, to: (1) allow you to participate in features we offer or to provide related customer service; (2) recognize you across the Redbox Platforms and across devices; (3) tailor content recommendations and offers we display to you, both on the Redbox Platforms and elsewhere online; (4) process a rental, purchase, or other transaction; (5) provide you with information, products, or services that you have requested or that we think may interest you; (6) investigate and prevent fraudulent transactions and other illegal activities or activities that violate our policies; (7) process your registration, including verifying your information is active and valid; (8) improve the Redbox Platforms or our services and for internal business purposes; (9) facilitate your job search via the Redbox Platforms and prepare related governmental and internal statistics reports; (10) contact you with regard to your use of the Redbox Platforms or any Redbox service and, in our discretion, changes to the Redbox Platform policies; and (11) for purposes disclosed at the time you provide your Personal Information or otherwise with your consent.  We may also use and share non-personal information in our discretion and we may use non-personal information, including information that has been de-identified (typically by using a mathematical process known as a “hash”), to make inferences about you and offers and content you may be interested in, to serve you with relevant advertising, and to allow others to do so.

**CHILDREN**  
The Redbox Platforms are not intended for use by anyone younger than the age of 13 and we do not knowingly collect Personal Information from children younger than age 13. If we learn that we have inadvertently collected Personal Information from a user who is younger than age 13, we will delete the information from our active databases.

**COMMUNITY FORUMS**  
The Redbox Platforms may offer message boards and other public areas ( **Community Forums)** where you can choose to interact with others and/or to post or submit content. Note that anything you choose to disclose in such a community forum is public.  It may be viewed, collected and used by others and the protections of this Privacy Policy will not apply. Think carefully before you post and use caution before disclosing any Personal Information. Please review the “User Comments and Postings” section of our [Terms of Use](http://www.redbox.com/rentalterms) for information on the rights that you grant to us in any content you choose to post in a community forum.

**DISCLOSURE OF INFORMATION TO THIRD PARTIES**  
Redbox may share non-personally identifiable information, such as information that has been de-identified, aggregated user statistics, or a Redbox identification or transaction number, with third parties in our discretion. We do not share your Personal Information with third parties for those third parties’ own direct marketing purposes unless you consent (opt-in or opt-out) to such sharing. California Residents, please see below for additional information on “Your California Privacy Rights.”

We may share the information we have collected about you, including Personal Information, as disclosed at the time you provide your information, as described in this Privacy Policy, with your consent, and in the following circumstances:

**When You Request That We Share Your Information**  
We may share information when you request that we do so. For example, you may be presented with an opportunity to receive information and/or marketing offers from one or more third parties. If you agree at that time to have your Personal Information shared, your Personal Information will be disclosed to that third party (or parties) and will be subject to their privacy practices. Or, you may choose to interact with a third party application or feature, through which information about you is shared. Please note that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of third parties. If you later decide that you no longer want to receive communications from a third party, you will need to contact that third party directly. <

**Third Parties Providing Services on Our Behalf**  
We may share information about you, including Personal Information, with third-party vendors to enable them to perform services on our behalf. Additionally, we may share various information relating to our users and fraudulent or potentially fraudulent activities with our fraud prevention and similar vendors, and they will use this information to help us and their other clients prevent fraudulent and illegal transactions.

**Sweepstakes, Contests and Promotions**  
We may offer sweepstakes, contests, and other promotions (any, a “ **Promotion** ”) that may require registration. If you choose to enter a Promotion, Personal Information may be disclosed to third parties or the public in connection with the administration of such Promotion, including, without limitation, as required by law or permitted by the Promotion’s official rules, such as on a winners list.

**Administrative and Legal Reasons**  
We may also transfer and disclose user information, including Personal Information, to third parties: (i) in the event we are required to respond to subpoenas or other legal process or if in our opinion such disclosure is required by law; (ii) at the request of governmental authorities conducting an investigation; or (iii) to protect and/or defend the [Terms of Use](http://www.redbox.com/rentalterms), the Redbox [Transaction Terms](http://www.redbox.com/transactionterms) or other policies applicable to a Redbox Platform or our services or to protect the personal safety, rights, property or security of Redbox, our customers, or a third party. We may also use Device Identifiers, including IP addresses, to identify users, and may do so in cooperation with copyright owners, Internet service providers, wireless service providers or law enforcement agencies in our discretion.

**Business Transfers**  
Redbox may share Personal Information with its parent, or its subsidiaries and affiliates, primarily for business and operational purposes. Redbox reserves the right to disclose and transfer all information related to a Redbox Platform, including Personal Information: (i) to a subsequent owner, co-owner or operator of a Redbox Platform or applicable database; or (ii) in connection with a corporate merger, consolidation, restructuring, bankruptcy, the sale of certain of Redbox’s ownership interests, assets, or both, or other company change, including, without limitation, during the course of any due diligence process.

**THIRD-PARTY ADVERTISING AND ANALYTICS COMPANIES**  
Redbox works with network advertisers, ad agencies and other advertising partners to serve Redbox ads online.  We also use analytics providers to provide us with information regarding the use of the Redbox Platforms and the effectiveness of our advertisements. You may also see ads on the Redbox Platforms and those ads may be served by a third party. These third parties may set and access their own tracking technologies on your device (including cookies and web beacons), and they may otherwise collect or have access to information about you, including Usage Information. Some of these parties may collect Personal Information over time when you visit the Redbox Platforms or other online websites and services. We may share non-personal information, including information that has been de-identified, Usage Information, and location information, with third party advertising companies, analytics providers and other third parties, including for the purpose of serving you more relevant ads.

We may use a variety of companies to serve our advertisements. Some of these companies are members of the Network Advertising Initiative (“NAI”) or the Digital Advertising Alliance (“DAA”) Self-Regulatory Program for Online Behavioral Advertising and you may want to visit the following webpages, which provide “opt-out” mechanisms for participating companies: <http://networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>; <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>.  You may also be able to opt-out from interest based advertising on your mobile device through your mobile device settings.  You may also opt-out from receiving targeted ads while on Redbox Platforms through your account settings as further described below in “Your Choices.” Please note opting out through these mechanisms does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads while online.

**HOW WE RESPOND TO “DO NOT TRACK” SIGNALS**  
Note that your browser settings may allow you to automatically transmit a “Do Not Track” signal to websites and online services you visit. Like many websites and online services, the Redbox Platforms do not alter their practices when they receive a “Do Not Track” from a visitor’s browser.  To find out more about “Do Not Track,” please visit www.allaboutdnt.com.

**CHANGING YOUR INFORMATION**  
You are responsible for maintaining the accuracy of the information you submit to us, such as your contact information provided as part of registration. Certain Redbox Platforms allow you to [correct or update](https://www.redbox.com/Account) certain Personal Information you have provided and to change your subscriptions or preferences regarding marketing information you receive from Redbox. Note that when you edit your Personal Information or change your preferences on a Redbox Platform, information that you remove may persist internally for Redbox’s administrative purposes or within backup media. If you have made any public postings on a Redbox Platform, these communications cannot generally be removed.

**YOUR CHOICES**  
Redbox offers you the following choices with regard to the information it collects through the Redbox Platforms:

**Targeted Advertising.** You may see third party advertisements on Redbox Platforms; We offer you the ability to opt-out from having your Redbox activity and other information about you used to serve you targeted ads.  You may opt-out via your Account settings.  Note that you must be logged in to opt-out (or opt-in).  Opting out does not mean you will no longer receive online advertising. It does mean that Redbox will no longer customize ads you see on Redbox Platforms based on your activities or profile information with Redbox. **** You may also opt-out from many third parties who serve online advertising, including some who serve Redbox ads elsewhere online, by visiting <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>; **** or <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>. **** Opting out does not mean you will not see any ads when browsing Redbox Platforms, but the ads you see will no longer be customized to you based on your profile or interactions with Redbox.

**Marketing Emails and Mobile Messages.** You may opt out of receiving marketing e-mails by following the opt-out instructions provided to you in those e-mails.  Please note that we reserve the right to send you certain communications relating to your account or use of the Redbox Platforms or Redbox services, such as administrative and services announcements.  These transactional account messages may be unaffected if you choose to opt out from marketing e-mails.

If you sign up to receive SMS or MMS messages from Redbox, you may unsubscribe from any SMS or MMS messages received by replying “STOP”.

With your consent, we may send promotional and non-promotional push notifications or alerts to your mobile device, and may in some cases do so based on your device’s physical proximity to a beacon.  You can elect to stop receiving those messages at any time by changing the notification settings on your mobile device.

**YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS**  
California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits residents of California to request certain details about how their personal information has been shared during the calendar year with third parties for those third-parties’ own direct marketing purposes, unless the business permits California residents to opt in to, or opt out of, this type of sharing. Redbox qualifies for this alternative option. As noted above, we will not share personal information about you with third parties for their own direct marketing purposes if you do not opt-in, or if you choose to opt-out, at the time Redbox offers you that choice.

If you are a California resident and you have questions about our practices with respect to sharing personal information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes and your ability to exercise choice, please send your request by email to [Questions@redbox.com](mailto:Questions@redbox.com) or write us at Attention Legal, Redbox Automated Retail, LLC, 1 Tower Lane, Suite 900, Oakbrook Terrace, Illinois 60181. You must put the statement “Your California Privacy Rights” in the subject field of your email or in the address line of your envelope. You must include your name, street address, city, state, and ZIP code. We are not responsible for notices that are not labeled or sent properly, or do not have complete information.

**THIRD PARTY CONTENT, SITES & DEVICES **  
The Redbox Platforms may contain content that is served by someone else or links to third-party content or web sites that Redbox does not control. This includes links from advertisers, sponsors and partners that may use our logo(s) as part of a co-branding relationship. You may also be able to access the Redbox Platforms through third-party devices and platforms, such as a set-top box, internet-connected TV, or similar device. The third-party operators and content providers may send their own cookies to your device, they may independently collect data or solicit Personal Information, and may or may not have their own published privacy policies. Redbox is not responsible for the privacy practices employed by any third party.

**SECURITY**  
Redbox takes commercially reasonable steps to protect and secure Personal Information. However, no data transmission over the Internet, by wireless transmission or any electronic storage of information can be guaranteed to be 100% secure.  Please note that we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information we collect, and you use the Redbox Platforms and our services and provide us with your information at your own risk. 

**CONSENT TO TRANSFER**  
Redbox is based in the United States the information we collect is governed by United States law. By accessing or using a Redbox Platform or providing us with any information, you consent to the transfer, processing and storage of your information in and to the United States and other countries, jurisdictions in which the privacy laws may not be as comprehensive as those in the country where you reside and/or are a citizen.
